Hey, Wade.
Good evening.
How are you doing?
DC.
Yeah, I've already read the first one.
What?
Sorry, what?
Lots of people are recommending it to me.
Yeah, I don't know why.
It's not that good.
It's fine.
I don't know.
It's definitely taken the zeitgeist.
Well, it definitely opens up on a pretty zany note.
Yeah, it stays pretty zany.
I don't know.
I mean, it's certainly not bad, right?
Like, it's just, I don't know how it rose to such like everybody talks about it.
Have you read Ready Player One?
Yes, that was the same sort of deal.
Okay.
So, all right.
Yeah.
Did you read Ready Player One?
What did you think of it?
Yeah, nostalgia entertainment.
It was, yeah, it's Forest Gump for Gen Xers or something.
Yeah, I don't understand either book.
Like, I've read them both, and I just, I don't get the appeal.
Like, they're fine.
They just, they're not great.
Like, they're just fine.
But yeah, people just go kind of nuts for them.
So,
I mean, I guess if you were looking for nostalgia, it might be what you're looking for.
Yeah, I mean, there's definitely a lot of, I mean, like I said, it's Forrest Gump for Gen X, right?
Like,
I don't know if you've read that one, but man, it's just, yeah, it's just nothing but like, hey, remember Reagan?
Hey, remember the, remember these?
Remember Kenny?
I didn't read Forest Gump, though.
No, I don't think you need to any more than I think you need to read Ready Player One or DCC.
Where's Cassadas?
I don't know.
I don't see any note in the Discord.
There he is.
Hey.
Hello.
Good evening.
Let's see if he joins.
What did I miss?
Thomas Jefferson.
We're just talking about this.
Yeah.
No, you got that part.
So I put the summary and the abbreviated summary and the abbreviated abbreviated summary, but the short version is the party went to Carved Up the Dragon.
Yeah, we got the double natural 20 on it on Invention.
You then went to the mine.
Went to the mine.
Why didn't we go to Phandalin?
Because it was on the way.
It's on the way.
Okay.
And while you were there, you discovered that there was a small situation.
Yes.
That was resolved.
Resolved peacefully.
You were lying to me.
And I did not take time to that.
There's always a situation with these people.
Nobody can do anything without us.
Just for the record.
It's open like a real manager.
It was handled.
Vukradin doesn't have to know all the details.
Okay.
Yeah.
We're learning to keep him out of the room.
Yeah, I don't want to know.
I don't want to know.
Don't talk about it.
Vukradin was kept in the dark.
Good.
And you arrived in Phandalin.
By the way, that dragon is fair trade.
Yeah.
All the like that magic item you got from him, that seemed totally fair trade to me.
Well, it's not actually a magic item.
It's a part for a magic item.
Okay.
It can be problems that you have to invest money with the dragon parts to get the super badass item.
And we don't quite have the money.
Oh.
All right.
So you arrived in Phandalin.
Harbin Wester, you know, pompously declared how happy he was to see you.
He made a point about applauding your role in defeating the threat of the dragon.
He congratulated you.
He said that this is precisely why he created the Privy Council to bring in the talent.
Seething rage.
There was a big festival set up, so that was great.
No, there was a big festival in your honor.
Great.
Yeah.
We did not get into this for festivals.
I'm just telling you what happened, right?
You asked me what.
Did I play?
Well, let me just tell you what happened.
We'll assume you played.
Oh, I feel back at them.
So after, but in the middle of the dinner, Ser Kaelen pulled you aside.
Actually, pulled Soma aside, and the rest of you followed and informed her that the Druids are at it again and that she really needs to go to the Druid Enclave and stop Soma, who's rabble-rousing folks.
Stop Adabra.
Didn't we have we have an Emerald Enclave quest?
Yes, this is it.
No, no, no.
We had a different one.
Make Lyra great again.
M-L-G-A.
Go to the Emerald Enclave with Lyra and persuade everyone that Lyra is awesome.
Yes.
So good point.
I should have added that Ser Kaelen said that the way she's planning to use it is to use Lyra's failure at the Withering Woods.
Apparently, Adabra went to see what happened and discovered you weren't quite truthful.
Okay, well, we'll be very persuasive.
I'm just telling you, so there's a meeting.
There is a meeting.
They're conspiring against us.
Right.
And so what you've learned, what Ser Kaelen said was that Soma's meteoric rise as an interventionist has alarmed Adabra.
And Adabra's trying to get the Emerald Enclave to denounce Soma.
And, you know, apparently.
Right.
And apparently, Ser Kaelen is the point Ser Kaelen made about her was that Adabra during the War of the Dragons, Adabra saw the damage caused by the people fighting the dragons and not by the dragons themselves and concluded that the problem was the people fighting the dragons,
not the dragons, not the cultists.
It's Ukraine's fault for Ukraine.
Exactly.
It was, yes, like basically.
Yeah.
Why are they resisting?
Yes, yes.
No, I mean, she's, that's, that's, that's, she, she's, she's not, she's just a delusion.
She's awful.
Yeah, I mean, she's, and I think she's very authentic in a real world kind of way.
Why did we save her?
Because I thought naturalists meant something else at the time.
Also, there was like 50 gold on the line, wasn't there?
Yes, I think it was 50 gold.
I think that was the main reason.
Right.
Yeah.
I'm sure that's the only reason we do anything.
I'll have to go look into that.
I'm pretty sure it was 50 gold.
It's 50 gold.
Yeah.
I'm curious.
All right.
So 40 pieces of silver.
Come on.
It was 30 pieces of silver.
Well, I mean, in the neverwinter exchange rate, yes.
Did I miss something?
Oh, yeah, we leveled up.
I don't know if.
Oh, you have to be hired one level higher.
What level are we?
We're six now.
Holy cow.
That's amazing.
Actually, to be quite honest,
we should be level seven.
No, we're level.
You're level seven now?
Yes, right?
Huh?
No, we're at level six now.
Six.
Yes.
Universal speech.
Okay, some questions about Phandalin Muller here.
Just before you go it, the answer was he needed organic, conflict-free, fair tree gold to fund his studio.
He refused to admit from looting.
The umbrage hill job was clean money.
So, yes, it was all about the money.
Yeah.
But because this is Vukradin, he doesn't remember this.
I've sort of came to the appreciate Vukradin doesn't see any conflict with any of his objectives.
He like uses his silver eloquence on himself.
I mean, if you can deceive yourself, you'll always be happy, right?
Right.
But he does object to people who do bad things.
He finds that offensive.
That's his Aasimar heritage.
Yeah.
Like, you know, evil for him is just wrong.
All right.
I mean, just by definition.
Yeah.
So you were going to ask about Phandalin.
Sorry.
Is this stale?
What?
Is this icon steel?
Which one?
On roll 20.
I don't know.
I haven't logged into roll 20, but maybe.
Ah, okay.
Long rest.
Did you raise yourself level?
Did you get up to level?
Did you love yourself to update?
I did.
Yeah.
Got some awesome new features.
Oh, can I ask which ones they are so I can groan from silver tongued to golden tongued when a creature adds one of your bardic inspiration dice to its ability check attack roll or saving throw and the roll fails the creature can keep the bardic inspiration die oh that's handy so keep it until it's useful until it succeeds yeah until it succeeds and also i can now talk to creatures in any language awesome i i have i have an important i'm useless no actually you're not useless anymore now you can talk to the bard what when you're a beast you couldn't talk to anybody now you can talk to the bard this is actually useful yeah i can only do that once once per long rest and for one hour okay oh by the way we had it we had we had a true gary moment gary discovered that he could cast bless four times per day oh yeah what for 10 minutes yes he has i i've got this which uh you've had that for like four levels now or something yeah yeah yeah dude blast is helpful yeah yes so he he's got bodis bless spells just so you all know my goodness uh and then there's the other thing that was then he's got an even really cool even cooler ability and then there's that one
oh yeah sure all right nice so so you were gonna have one for Brewbarry yes who can then shrug it off oh no she should not be there yeah all right veteran is dead veterans are dead uh yes there's no combat you're you're you're currently in Phandalin talking to Ser Kaelen outside of the temple of the fander's searing pain of justice okay and then there's like two spider-man here too did did i hear that like no that's jenna rosco that's not spider-man Valphine have i have i understand that's just telling me where he lives qualifies as a charity is that i heard that from from custadis is that accurate that's a charity yeah is your church like a charity yeah that can people donate yeah you know because i was thinking um it's very important that if we can't find the rightful owners of all these items that they go to charity yeah that's definitely true it's like i lost and found an episode of uh flintstones or something i mean we need to try to return them to their rightful owners but sometimes not possible
well yeah by the way as we arrived back in town we needed to do um a religious parade
yes don't forget bryn and uh giles were showed their self-fundraiser if you will yes for the children yes it involves uh self-flagellation through the through the town was it fruitful i don't know you didn't tell me
So the ritual, you did when what's his name, when the Valphine arrived, Bryn and Giles, who were the two most recent converts to the Temple of Lothander's searing pain of justice, showed up scarred and sunburnt.
And they were very excited.
And, you know, they talked about the purifying essence of the pain of the sun.
That's right.
That, you know, this was.
Meanwhile, just so you know, Dave, just to bring you up to speed, Soma has experienced a level of no, sorry, not Nova.
Lathander has definitely reached out and made Valphine aware that he approves of the direction he's taking the church.
Well, of course.
Since you're, of course, oblivious to all politics in the area, I won't explain to you why this is important.
No, no.
Sounds like the charity is going very well.
Yeah.
Actually, ironically, Vukradin's lack of interest in what's going on matches Dave's lack of interested lore.
Funny how that works.
Hold on.
I need to get myself a soda.
Searing pain of justice.
Funny.
You didn't see the picture of the temple, right?
It was a new picture.
Not the new picture, it's old picture.
Okay.
It's an old picture.
Vukradin's moral leadership guides your decisions.
My moral leadership doesn't guide anyone's decisions.
You're a little more moral than most of us.
Yeah, but I don't guide you guys.
No, no.
Actually, you stand in the way more than guide.
That seems more accurate.
Yeah.
All right.
Well, are we off to make Lyra great again?
I guess we are.
I will be very persuasive.
There was some subtle railroading on the going there.
Yes.
That's all right.
It was on the quest tracker.
It was.
I need to do it eventually.
I'm not complaining.
Okay.
We still have.
Yeah, we still missed a bunch of stuff, though.
Lyra.
Okay, I got to figure out my strategy for this.
This is going to be challenging.
All right.
So I presume we wake up in the morning and we head out to the forest where the meeting is going to be held.
It would seem like the prudent thing to do.
All right.
Do we all need to go?
You just send Sona.
You guys can go have fun.
Let's go.
I like Lyra.
We need to help her.
She's a good person.
You know, we're going to piss off the Druids, though.
They're not going to.
Lyra's a Druid.
Yeah, but so's Adabra.
And this is part of the whole schism.
You're going to end up losing half your fans there.
Oh.
That's why I have such a silver tongue.
I mean, if you can sit on that fence, friends, if you can dance that fence, man.
All right.
Okay.
What am I trying to do here?
All right.
Okay.
So
as you're, so you get directions to the relevant event, of course.
And you arrive at what can only be described as a council of druids.
And Adabra is there waiting for you, waiting for you to speak.
She knew we were coming.
Everybody gets heart inspiration.
Yes, hold on.
You're not a bear, right?
No, I can only be in a bear for like two hours at a time.
Hold on, let me clear this.
All right.
See if I can do that.
And did I update?
I don't know if I updated the stats here.
Nope.
51 is the current.
Okay.
Make sure everything else is accurate because, you know.
All right.
So actually, I'm sorry, I should have misspoke.
As you're approaching the council, Thomas, who was one of Lyra's agents, looks as if one of the guys who worked with Lyra sees you and he wants to talk to you for a few moments.
Is Lyra here?
He's here.
Oh, where's Lyra?
Well, do you ask him?
Yeah, I'm asking.
I'll only speak to Lyra.
He explains that Lyra goes, Lyra is currently at the council.
That's where we are.
No, no, you're on your way.
I'm sorry.
I made a mistake.
Oh, we're in route.
Yes.
This is a random encounter.
We're on there right now.
Okay.
All right.
He goes, I must.
He goes, okay, so you get, yeah, so he's Lyra's in the council.
Adabra is looking to punish Lyra.
She's very upset.
Lyra did nothing wrong.
Punish how?
Punish how.
He pauses and says, well, Adabra doesn't have the authority to ban Lyra, but she does have the power to ostracize her and cause her and to have everyone turn on her and treat her with indifference.
Who has the authority?
Well, he pauses and goes, This is the Emerald Enclave.
We don't really do authority.
I can hippies.
We don't have top-down hierarchies.
Okay.
Yeah.
And he pauses and said, although Rydoth, who is the nominal druid, who is the nominal head of this chapter of the enclave, isn't here.
And Adabra called the meeting while he wasn't precisely to achieve her objectives.
You need to be careful if you're going there.
And he looks to see.
Where's Rygoth?
He's out of town.
Okay.
Hang on.
He's out of town.
What does that mean?
Like, what did he need to do?
Why did he have to go?
Why isn't he here?
Because he pauses: the ways of druids and what they need to do is not something they communicate to the likes of meme.
Can you describe Rygeth to me?
He does.
Okay.
Is Rygeth aware that this council is taking place?
No.
What would Rygeth think if the council were taking place?
He would be totally fine with it.
Oh, really?
So he supports the.
I know he's a big believer in open communications and open channels.
Okay.
Oh, he'll just always call more meetings, you mean?
Yes.
Okay.
When you say that, he actually says, yes.
Rydoth believes in discussion and speaking.
He believes consensus.
I think he would, if he knew this council was taking place, he would want to be here.
No.
I don't know.
I don't know what he's.
You don't know.
So he doesn't give a shit.
What is this role as first druid?
It's just sort of like Thomas goes, you know what, Vukradin?
I've given you all I can.
I need to go to the meeting.
Okay.
All right.
I just want to be clear: like, if we could, if we could contact Rygeth, if it made a difference, you know, we'd get a hold of him, but it sounds like it won't make a difference.
No, I mean, no, it won't.
He's not going to stop Aldabra from speaking.
And he couldn't stop it anyway.
But then why did she call it while he was gone?
Why not?
Because she wants to shun Soma and she wants to avoid any possibility of you think Rygath would be on my side?
I have no idea.
I think he should be there, though.
Do you know how far away he is?
He goes, he pauses.
Thomas says, look, if you want to go fetch Rydoth, you can go fetch Rydoth.
By the time you fetch him, so Adabra will have had her meeting and had her say.
It is your choice.
Okay.
Gonna keep this one in my back pocket.
All right.
So you show up at the council.
And Adabra sees you.
And as she steps forward and says, and looks at you, and looks at she doesn't look at, she doesn't neither look at Soma nor Vukradin.
She kind of looks at the room.
As far as she's concerned, you guys don't exist.
I will be brief.
I am not here to argue philosophy with you.
I'm here to tell you what I found.
Three weeks ago, I went to the whispering wood myself.
I walked to the spring grove.
The treant is dead.
Not wounded, not sleeping, dead.
Roots collapsed.
Crown black.
The grove that Lyra's chapter was assigned to protect is gone.
I pressed Lyra's people on what happened.
Their account did not match what I found.
I pressed further.
They named the bard.
I then spoke with two others who were present at the grove that night.
Their account also did not match.
What they described is not what was reported to us.
The party concealed what happened.
They did not make a mistake and tell us.
They made a choice.
I want you to understand what that choice cost.
The last time I spoke with this party, I believed the ritual had failed.
The tree had still lived.
When I heard there was a planar creature collecting materials near the grove, I was, I will say this plainly, pleased.
I called it a planar magpie.
I said it was the world working as it should.
I gave the fard five gold pieces for what he told me that day.
I believed him.
Now I have walked to the grove itself.
The treant is dead.
The creature is still there.
What I called the world healing itself was the world responding to a wound I was not told had been made.
He did not only lie to Lyra's people, he lied to me.
These are the facts.
A sacred grove is dead.
A report was falsified.
And I gave gold to the man who falsified it because he is very good at what he does.
I'm not asking you to condemn anyone today.
I'm asking you to look at what I found before you listen to anyone tell you what it means.
She steps back.
She doesn't sit.
She is done.
As you look across the room, you notice that there's two people that you notice Falcon is sitting next to her and looking at her very approvingly.
This is Falcon, the tavern guy.
Yes.
He's looking very approvingly.
Got his ear.
So do you guys say anything or do you sit there?
So I just want to press on this account.
You said that there were some witnesses that you talked to.
Who did you talk to?
Lyra.
And I witnessed it with my own two eyes.
You went three weeks after and saw that the Treant had died.
Yes.
Right.
So between, how much time passed between when you heard this account, which you claim was false, and then you saw that the Treant was dead?
How much time between those two points?
She goes, I did two weeks.
Two weeks.
A lot can happen in two weeks.
How do you know that what you heard from, I believe you were referring to me, wasn't true and that the Treant died within that two-week period before you personally went and saw that it had died?
You don't know that.
He turns to make sure I got the right guys.
He turns to one of Lyra's people and says, Thomas, what happened?
Thomas says, Lyra asked us to go deal with the metastasized treant.
We tried.
We failed.
The party showed up.
They killed it.
Okay, that's what he says.
He turns to Lyra.
What happened?
She turns to Lyra.
Lyra says the same thing, and then proceeds to try to defend herself by explaining, saying, Look, this was a planar infestation.
Things were going south.
The grove was bleeding.
Oh, yeah.
Okay, I need to have a sidebar conversation.
Do you guys want to throw Lyra under the bus or Lyra and Thomas under the bus?
You want to throw ourselves under the bus?
Like, what do you want to do?
I don't know why they've decided to be so honest and confess to a crime when they didn't need to, but apparently they did.
Well, that sounds like they got very poor counsel.
This is a sidebar conversation.
No, no, I know.
This is a sidebar.
If I had been their attorney, I would have advised them to remain silent.
Soma, roll a nature check.
All right.
I assume we're in the woods.
21.
Okay.
And I could bardic inspire that if I need to, but you understand what's going on.
They don't think they did anything wrong.
Yeah, no, obviously.
Right.
As far as they're concerned, she's accusing them of doing something that they don't feel she did anything wrong.
They did anything wrong.
So they're not confessing to a crime.
They're just, yeah, stating facts as they see them.
As far as they're concerned, this is exactly what happened.
And they're damn proud of it.
And that's what Lyra kind of said.
She's not embarrassed that she did that.
She did the right thing as far as she's concerned.
All right, Soma, you're the druid.
What do you want me to argue?
You decide.
I can argue any point of view.
Yeah.
I mean, my goal is to shut down Adabra.
And to me, it seems like Lyra is the key to doing that.
So we want to convince the crowd that what Lyra did was correct.
Yes.
But these people who are non-interventionists, I cannot persuade them to become interventionists.
That is beyond my ability.
At this point, probably, yeah.
Okay.
So you just want a schism?
I mean, I think the schism is already happening.
I think we just need to sort of, you know, light it up.
I could rally, we could, you know, rally for the interventionists, right?
Like, we're proud interventionists.
We're forming our own group.
Come join us.
Screw these non-interventionists.
Rah-rah, go team.
I mean, you can stick to your principles and say we did the right thing.
And yes, we killed the treant, and that had to happen.
The treant was going to take over the whole thing.
The treant was going to kill us.
It was a self-defense.
Yeah, that's that's I mean, it's self-defense for us and for the whole the land, really.
Like the land was being corrupted.
Embrace your somaness.
Okay, well, I don't think denying what happened is going to work since these people don't seem to understand how trials work.
This is what happens when you go hang out with a bunch of hippies.
I suppose there's one other thing we run.
Let's blow this blow that on Adabra.
I want to see what the hell's up with her.
What?
Oh, the residence of truth.
Do you remind me what it does?
It doesn't make sense.
You can use this ability once for long rest.
Oh, copyright.
How do I copy the actual?
I think I can see her.
She's wisdom saving throw against my spell DC seven.
Being mentally controlled, magically manipulated, or consciously lying.
Yeah.
The answer to all of those.
Is no.
Yeah.
No, she's a true believer.
She's a true believer.
This is all.
All right.
So we're going to force it.
She's just insane.
So the plan is force the schism, rah-rah, go interventionists.
We're going to try to persuade as many people as we are.
And I'm going to also contact Rygoth and inform him of what we were doing.
All right.
How are you doing that?
Just so I know?
Sending.
Folks, have we.
Oh, somebody has subscribed to you.
Okay.
Yeah.
You did ask.
Could you send me the what you sent him so I have it in my notebook with my notes?
Like, what do you tell him?
Like, you've got a coup going on here.
We're taking care of it.
I mean, we're definitely fomenting one.
More of a schism.
We are interventionists and we are proud of our interventionism and we are going to fight for our forest.
You can't really have a coupon when there's a lot of people.
We're on the non-interventionist.
All right.
That's that's fair.
Peacefully.
Can you can you beat them with a like whip them up with a rousing song like every uh like every uh you know sitcom?
So the other thing you notice, the other thing you know, as you're looking around, okay.
So, okay, so what is it?
What is it you literally say?
Well, I'm not the, yeah, I didn't know.
I mean, like, what Soma, what do you say?
I'll let Vukradin like, you know, help you with the phraseology.
Go for it, Wade.
You're the Druids, so you're the ones who are looking to, just so you know.
Yeah, I mean, I tell them that the land is hurting and intervention is the only way out.
We are here to protect the land at all costs.
And if that makes us interventionists, then so be it.
We're proud.
We're loud.
All right.
Okay.
The conversation.
The conversation starts to rotate.
At this point in time, the Falcon starts getting involved, you know, pointing out that interventionism only causes harm.
Hold on.
If we had an intervention, intervene.
Hold on, Dave, Dave, Dave, Dave, I need to give you a piece of information.
Oh, okay.
But before you.
So, I'm going to give this to you
because it happened a while ago.
So, you would have probably forgot.
Chat.
I'm going to say Mr.
Dave.
Let me see.
Where are you?
More Year Root, right?
Yeah, that's him.
All right.
So I just gave you a sent you a private Discord message.
So Falcon is, you know, defending of defending Adabra.
All right.
Yeah, I just.
That's a good plan.
I like that.
He goes, he goes, he pauses, and somebody makes some comment about how he supports Adabra.
And he goes, I came because someone finally sat long enough to listen.
You can keep cheering your victories.
I've seen what comes after them.
All right.
So he's basically goes, and she's right.
She's right about what needed to happen.
You all wanted it simple.
Well, this is what simple looks like.
People are, trees are dead because of men like him.
And he points to you and to you, to Vukradin.
Wow.
Betrayed.
You made an enemy.
So what do you want to do with him?
You can ignore him.
You can throw him under the bus.
So
the ring.
Oh.
The one that you found while snooping around.
Yep.
So what do you want to do?
Give it to him.
Remind him of his lies.
Well, no, how do you frame it?
How do I frame it?
Yeah.
So you just present the ring and say, here, remember, he has the ring.
You don't have it.
He has the ring.
Yeah, I was checking our image.
No, you returned it to him.
Yeah, I think you left everything in place.
It's very, I mean, you would have stole something from him.
Unlike you.
Yeah.
So I don't have the ring.
Nope.
But you did recall what it looked like and that it had a sign of a lightning bolt.
Yeah.
Hmm.
So what do you guys want to do?
Do you want to tell them what's going on?
Can I pull them aside?
Yes, you can pull them aside.
I mean, the discussion's going on.
This is, you know, a conclave.
This is not, you know, like something, you've got periodically druids who like speak for 20 minutes on rambling topics.
You've got Homer Simpson moments.
Yeah.
Right.
So there's plenty of opportunity to talk.
So, man, like, what's going on here?
Like, I thought we were talking about.
Oh, you're trying to talk to the Falconists?
Yeah, the drop-in.
Like, why are you.
Why are you like, why are you pointing me out in front of this group?
What did I do?
He goes, you intervened, and in your intervention, people died.
Uh-huh.
Okay.
And Dabra sees it clearly.
Yes.
I hear you.
Yeah.
So you really, you really believe this?
Yes, of course I do.
Didn't you, didn't, weren't you an adventurer?
Like, didn't you used to intervene?
Like, why the change of heart?
And he goes, and look what it got me.
Okay.
It got you.
As far as I can tell, it got you a beautiful hunting lodge and lots of fame and glory and a whole life built on a lie.
Got you a lot, that intervention.
But now, now you're going to screw me over.
He looks at you with contempt.
I could tell everybody about what you did.
He goes, what?
About how you intervened.
And he goes, ever since I spoke to Adabra, I have learnt the error of my ways.
Well, then, you should have no trouble repenting in front of the group.
And explaining that you made up in front of the room and says, you are right.
You are right.
I want to hear him.
Abandoned my boy.
He goes, the silky tongued liar, like he calls you.
Wow.
Right.
Has dared to question, to tell, dare me to tell you what happened.
It is true.
He pauses.
I was the one.
I was an adventurer once.
And I once believed that the path to solving the universe was to intervene.
And I once wanted to go fight the dragons.
And I failed to fight the dragons.
And I have learned that all the pain and misery that happened after that, yes, I had some baubles.
And yes, I had some money.
But what happened?
Once again, the nature tore it down.
Once again, the Falcon Lodge was burnt.
Once again, I asked heroes to intervene to protect my lodge.
And what did they do?
They did nothing.
And my lodge burned down.
Okay.
We tried.
Yeah.
Wow.
Okay.
I think I'm done.
I'm going to walk away.
You're walking away.
I'm going back to Phandalin.
You all can stay.
Okay.
I do not like the personal insults.
Hold on.
I'm not interested in helping Lyra anymore.
I'm not interested in this.
Well, hold on.
No, I'm straight up.
I'm done.
Okay.
You're outrage.
No, I'm not.
I'm not yelling.
I'm not screaming.
No, no, I mean, but you're just like, this is.
Right.
I'm just leaving.
Okay.
All right.
So you're left here.
Boy.
Without the silver tongue, I'm doomed.
Well, I mean, you could try to convince him to stay.
I mean, I don't know if it's possible.
No, no, I don't.
No, I respect that.
I mean, he's impetuous.
I understand.
Yeah, no, I think that's totally within character.
Give yourself an inspiration point, Dave.
I think that is totally within your character's perspective.
So what do we got?
We got douchebag over here thinking that he's got a moral high ground for being one way and seeing the air.
Before you leave, Dave, do you want to tell Soma what you learned about the Falcon or nothing?
You just like storm out?
You just like walk away?
Okay.
Brewbarry, of course, turns to you and says, Do you want me to kill him?
Dave.
What?
I'm gone.
No, no, no.
As you're walking away, Brewbarry says.
No, I don't have anything to say to Brewbarry.
He asks you whether you want me to kill him.
I heard you.
No.
No response.
So Brewbarry is kind of like wondering, turns to the two of you and says, Do we kill all these people or do we leave?
We don't kill them all.
Without the Druids, the land is even more screwed than, you know, with half of them.
Right.
So this is an opportunity for you to embrace your inner interventionism.
As you look around the room, what you gather is that most of the people kind of maybe agree with you,
but they're looking for a reason to agree with you.
They're all kind of, you know, under Adabra's clutches.
No, no, they're not.
I mean, that's actually what you're noticing: is that other than the Falcon and the other guy who's sitting next to her, nobody seems to be speaking in her favor.
Wait, who's the other guy?
He's somebody you haven't met.
Now you can go talk to, you can go talk to him.
I want to know who he is.
Yeah.
Okay.
I want to know that the, you know, I guess there's a trio of interventionists who have their clutches.
Naturalists, naturalists.
They're naturalists.
All right.
You're right.
I mean, yeah, it's kind of like hard to keep track of who's who.
It's just, it's all inverted, man.
Up is down, black is white.
So, yeah, I ask him to speak up.
All right.
So he introduces himself as, hold on, let me just make sure.
Let me just make sure I got the right name.
But Carver, no.
What?
No, I'm kidding.
All right, sorry.
Falcon, who you talked to?
Aldric Stone Path.
Aldric, I definitely don't recognize that name.
Yes.
So you look at him.
He's a new face.
He's human.
He's early 40s, weather.
So, as that's going on, as that's going on, she's like, as this is going on forward, Santopoulos arrives.
What about Aldric?
So, while you're about to approach Aldric, Santopoulos arrives.
I'm just telling you, like, so you can either see what he has to say or you can talk to Adric.
What would you like to do?
I want to talk to Aldric.
All right.
So, Santopoulos sees you all and just sits there.
Everybody's kind of like, oh my God, the big arrived.
He looks at you and he pauses.
How do you want to approach the conversation?
I just want to ask, I haven't heard from you.
You seem to be standing out in the crowd along with these two.
He explains that he's been in the mountains for 40 years, 15 years, mapping out all the mountains.
And that he observes that he starts talking about, you know, he goes,
he's like, talks of like, he goes, I've spent 50 years in these mountains.
I know every valley looked like before.
I've been told in order that nothing can be done and nothing needs to be done, right?
She is the first person who asked me what I actually saw.
During the War of the Dragons?
No, and what he's saying is like, he's going like, no, no, not about the War of the Dragons.
The mountains.
We've had problems with orcs.
We've had problems with disturbances of nature.
Nobody wants to talk about them.
But Adabra wanted to listen.
And she wants them to all fall apart.
And that's your solution?
What do you mean by fall apart?
Her solutions have other, you know, you've got problems with orcs.
You've got problems with dragons.
You've got problems with all these other things.
She's bringing in yet another problem: these planar anomalies, these infestations, these, you know, these other blights on the land.
I don't know how you don't see those as a problem as well, sir.
Read role at DC 13 insight or persuasion.
Oh, dear.
And so while you're talking about this, wait, well then, before you're talking about that, somebody turns to them.
There you go.
19 insight.
All right.
So you've described the peaks problem precisely.
What does Adabra say the solution is?
Right?
I mean, Adabra says let nature take its course and get obliterated, basically.
And then all of a sudden, when she suddenly stops,
and Aldric stops, right?
Like you all of a sudden sort of like made it impossible for him to ignore the consequences of his support for Adabra.
Yeah.
Right?
Hadabra, realizing what's going on, says, she goes, she goes, the displacement is downstream of the intervention.
The answer is to stop the cascade by withdrawing.
The ecosystem finds equilibrium without help.
Equilibrium comes in many forms.
One of these equilibriums could be the end of everything, of all life.
That's not the equilibrium I'm here to protect.
Right.
So, but this causes like the things sort of shift.
You can sort of feel that the mood has shipped decidedly against Adabra.
Adabra's furious.
She's like.
She's not, she wasn't, she was expecting Vukradin to like twist the word.
She wasn't expecting you.
Well, don't insult the bard.
Yeah, she was not expecting you of all people to be like.
She looks at Aldrich.
She's like, you can see the seething rage inside her verm.
At this point in time, San Popoulos sort of announces himself.
I'm sorry, I forget who San Popolos is.
He's the centaur.
Oh, right, right, right, right, right.
Okay.
All right.
Let's see.
The centaur we saw outside of the cave with the sword?
Yes, yes, yes.
Yeah.
Okay.
All right.
Did he watch us when we were up on top of the mountain?
No, no, he left.
Remember, he brought you to the edge.
Yes, because he said that his hooves were not suitable for mountain climbing.
He's not goat, he's a horse.
Yes, he goes, I'm a horse.
I'm not a ghost.
All right.
He was quite favorable to us, you know, like at the time that he was taking us up there, right?
I mean, he wanted us to intervene.
Yeah, what he said is there's idiots on both sides.
Well, yeah, there's plenty of stupid to go around.
Right, that was actually his line.
The idiots on one side and idiots on the other side.
Pure interventionism and pure naturalism are both follies.
Yes.
All right.
So he arrives.
He looks, he comes, Soma, good to see you.
You are still carrying that.
He points to your staff.
Never leaves home without it.
And he notices that it's, you know, different.
Got a few more leaves.
Yes, more green.
Yes, he goes, I know whose staff that is.
I know what it means that Meryl gave it to her.
He did not give it for sentiment.
He gave it because he pitched her.
He picked her.
Right.
It's just a staff.
Isn't it?
There's a role and insight check.
Another one?
All right.
Yes, I'm just because I'm in my acting machine.
Oh, there we go.
Let's go to.
I can bardically inspire that with a D10, I think.
Yes, you can.
Gary, you can use your insight as well.
Since you're a drow in a political situation, I'll let you even roll it with advantage.
I already rolled it 25.
Do you want me to roll that with advantage?
No, I don't need you to roll that with advantage.
Do you want to help Soma or do you want to see her flail?
I don't know that I have a lot of stake in this nature thing, but Soma's kind of helpful.
Sure.
You need a place to enjoy the sun.
Yeah.
Sure.
If there's like a subtle nudge I can give Soma.
Yeah, so the subtle nudge she gives you is that Meryl is extremely well respected by all of these druids.
That he's not just some random druid.
He's just a drifter.
No, no, he wasn't.
That's the point.
He was a very important druid.
And then apparently he picked you.
Right?
All the turtles in the land.
Yes.
Of all the turtles in all the land, he decided to pick you.
So like you're, you're like, this like, and so she's not going to attack Meryl.
Like attacking Meryl would not work.
Right.
And so, because I'm basically Meryl's bearer now.
Yes.
And so like, and so that's sort of the thing.
Then he goes, he sits down.
I have news.
Corbin is dead.
Sister Kaella walked out.
She's gone to the wind.
Corbin?
Yes.
As in our Corbin?
Our quarry?
Yeah, you left a second-level fighter with a 10th-level assassin.
This was not smart of us.
And Bony stood by and did nothing.
You guys didn't turn them in when you got to Phandalin?
I thought we did that.
No, they left them in the mine, remember?
Yeah.
Why'd you leave them in the mine?
You were the one.
I'm gone for one week and you don't take care of the criminals properly.
Wait, what?
What?
We left them in the mine?
You left them when you left the Dragon Barrow.
Oh, you're saying we were left to go to the Dragon Barrer.
Yeah.
No, when you left from the Dragon Barrow, you were under time pressure.
And so you decided to leave Sister Kaella with Corbin.
I remember that.
Yes.
And so Sister Kaella escaped from her clutches and killed Corbin.
We would have known that before.
They would have known that last week, right?
When the women had to go to camp.
No, no, because you guys left them in Dragon Barrow because you couldn't bring them along because you had to go on the horses very quickly.
Yeah.
Or we left them in Dragon Barrow.
Yes.
Well, there's one less of them left there.
Or one viewer, whatever.
Yeah, he's random MPC.
You know, we're not going to lose sleep on it.
I'm not.
I mean, I feel a little bad.
I'm sorry.
I feel a little bad.
I'll take him off.
Hold on, hold on.
He's not, what is his name?
He's not that guy from that other village.
Parnest.
What was his name?
Wallace?
Wallace.
He's not Wallace.
No, Wallace, I actually cared about.
Yeah, Wallace actually caused damage and helped you attack.
We still have Boney, right?
Yeah, yeah, he's still a Baron.
Yeah, Boney's still my sister.
I care a lot more about Bony.
I care about it.
What?
Sister Kaella owes me.
She escaped.
All right, that's fine.
She, well, yeah, all right.
She escaped.
All right.
Now I've got another quest is reclaim her.
I'll put it on the tracker.
Jesus Christ.
Bounty Hunch.
How many times have we had to chase her down?
It's like a villain du jour in a sitka or a serial.
Corbin's revenge.
So Adabra turns.
Adabra turns to him and says, See, this is the price of interventionism.
Dead bodies everywhere by careless, careless intervention.
I'm not here to listen to that.
And he points, he points to some.
And she goes, and then as Santopoulos turns to her and says, I am not on your side.
I'm not on this.
I'm telling you what my people saw and what happened.
Yeah.
This was not a fault of interventionism.
This was, you know, human nature, as it were.
Do you own up to the mistake, or are you going to try to sugarcoat it?
No, no, I mean, I'm with the honest druids, right?
Like, it's I'm not the liar that Vukradin is.
So you, you go like.
The speak of letting Corbin get killed?
Yes.
Okay.
This was this was more platting on our lives.
You're calling me a liar, too?
Everyone call me a liar tonight.
I can't embellish things appropriately.
Sorry, he lacks the feet of the silver tongue, Vukradin.
That's what we're doing.
I can't sugarcoat.
How about that?
The ask was: do I sugarcoat her or do I fuss up?
I'm not sugarcoating it.
I cannot cannot embellish.
All right.
Well, Corbin was not one of the faithful.
So I don't, not that I care about him too much.
So Cora Hilla owes me, and I think she's a good recruit for the church.
Corbin was indebted to the carver, basically, who, you know, we intervened upon, by the way.
I'll have you know, the carver would have been running around in a white dragon wrecking.
White dragon.
Yeah.
Okay, so you're embracing, you're embracing the moment.
You are okay.
Getting a little flustered myself.
So you're a little flustered yourself.
I'm still a little flustered.
All right.
At this point in time, the meeting has gone on for long enough, and a recess is called.
Right.
All right.
But before that recess, then after a few minutes, they suddenly realize they didn't hear about Lyra, what happened with Lyra.
Right.
They've been like arguing amongst themselves that they forgot the person.
So they bring in Lyra and she explains what happened.
She goes that, well, the forest, there was a planar rift.
The planar rift was damaging the forest.
If nobody took care of, there was nothing that could be done.
We needed to stop the planar rift from damaging more of the trees of the family.
So we did what we thought.
We thought there was a ritual that we could use, and it didn't work.
Adabra says, yes, but the treant is dead.
The interplanar treant?
Yes.
Yeah, that's.
I'm not going to cry for that.
That treant was going to bring a lot more manifestations and horror with it.
You remember some of the things that you saw, the distorted distorted L, the distorted.
Yeah, we saw a talking L.
Well, no, I guess it wasn't talking.
It was distorted.
Yeah.
Oh, and the dwarves in the other place.
No, we've encountered these anomalies.
They're not of this world.
They're not fit to be in this world.
Do you bring up the Axelholm incidents where you saw home?
That was what the dwarves were.
The dwarves that have been twisted by the oh god, man, that one made no sense.
Yeah, that was, I mean, those guys were just weird as fuck.
All right.
Do you bring that up?
Yeah, I absolutely do.
Yeah, we've seen things.
Do you bring up the fact that do you bring up the fact other things that you remember?
You remember about Aletra, you remember about the KP incident, you remember about the end, you know, the things that you've learned about that.
Do you bring any of that up or do you keep that to yourself?
Do you bring up that there was some drought involved?
I don't know.
I'm not going to bring up the drow at the moment.
And also bring up that, you know, if left unchecked, the Talos is starting to blight the land itself.
All right.
And that's an example of interventionism.
Yeah.
We're seeing, we're seeing, I mean, given that the Falcon's cabinet was overtaken by Talos members.
Talosians.
Talosians, yeah.
You know, and it's, and it's weird, you know, the Falconer asked us to intervene, but now he's an anti-interventionist.
Just saying, you know, he's mad that we failed to intervene, and yet.
Yeah, he's upset.
You get the sense that there's something that's upsetting him.
Well, he lost his summer home.
All right.
Okay.
So the meeting closes.
You definitely.
Do I know what's happening to whom?
Falcon.
Oh, you're going to go try to figure out what's going on with the Falcon?
Sure.
All right.
Well, so.
Or we do that in an intermission.
Hold on.
Okay, I'm just trying to remember what happened.
I thought it was like one of those summaries.
There's one of those summaries where I didn't take good notes.
It's like okay.
If you forget then, it's fine.
Real life is icky that way.
I know.
Okay, roll an insight check 18.
23.
All right.
I couldn't remember what happened, and I don't trust my notes.
So I'm going to go, I'm going to let the dice decide things.
That was a hard enough die roll.
So you remember that there was something that the story of the Falcon is complicated because of his relationship and his loss.
So he was like a treasure hunter, right?
He was a former adventurer, yeah.
Former adventurer.
Yes.
And then he retired.
He wait.
Okay, so just to be clear.
He's had some odd travelers come through his place.
All right.
He was upset about the encroaching orcs.
That's what we're calling.
Okay, so here's what you do know.
He knows that you know that you know that he had this ring, right, that belonged to.
Do we know that?
I thought.
Yeah, you do.
I just double-checked.
Okay.
You know about the horde that he went up to go hunt kill Imrith and found didn't find Imrith dead and found some petty gold.
You know about him lying about his accomplishments
and you know that his companions died.
All right.
Died or were murdered.
Well, that they were killed by Imrith, actually.
Yeah.
So you know all of those things and you also can sense that he's like, he's very bitter about something.
So how do you want to approach him?
Gary?
So just to be clear, just to be clear, just to make sure that Dave at least perhaps hears this, the problem was that Dave attacked, did not approach him with, like, tried to question the facts.
Right.
And that is also critical about him taking stuff from the horde.
Right, right.
Yeah.
Yes.
There was like.
So how would you want to approach it?
Like.
Well, he knows that we had tried to go on that mission to the internet.
Failed.
Right.
Yeah.
We were overwhelmed.
Roll an insight check.
Another insight check?
Yes, yes.
All right.
Sure.
25.
All right.
You're.
It's plus 10.
But I'm just, that's a very high.
So, so your insight, what your insight is telling you is that there is something, but this is a guy who keeps losing things.
Keeps losing things.
Right.
Like, he's intervened again and again.
And every time he tries to intervene, bad things happen.
He's just giving up on life.
Right.
So that's sort of his angle.
And so Adabra has told him that the answer is that he was intervening.
So he's gone full nihilist and just is going to lie back and take it.
Right.
You know, dragons can be killed.
So how do you want to approach him?
Browsing speech.
I think I'd start with apologize for not succeeding yet on the things he asked us to do, but we do plan to, you know, make our offer at some point.
And didn't we give him like a share of the gold mine or something?
Gold mine, sure.
I think he did.
Yeah.
Or he had a share of the gold mine.
So like we're making progress on that for him.
It required a lot of intervention with the leave that to the side that we had to intervene with the wererats to get them to like, you know, do their jobs properly and get the gold flowing again.
All right.
So, okay.
So you want to.
We're business partners.
Oh, okay.
So you bring that up.
All right.
And do you tell him what you guys have done to make it more progress getting this mine going?
He goes suddenly, it just kind of causes him to just.
It cracks him.
There's like he just says nothing and stares at the floor.
Adabra at this point in time is furious.
Like she is beyond livid.
Like, like, she starts, she's like, wants to lecture.
Like, she starts, you know, you know how those like protesters who left-wing protesters who start spewing lines of text that make no sense involving words that are increasingly complicated that you can't figure out whether they actually represent the English language.
Right.
Sure.
Or the anti-colonial, you know, your colonial mindset and your interventionist mindset.
Everything's a microaggression.
Right.
Yeah.
You know what I'm talking about, right?
So she goes, I mean, she does the moral equivalent of that as a druid in the Forgotten Realms.
At this point in time, one of the other druids says, I think it is time for us to call a meeting.
And he says to Soma, he seems very gracious to you.
He says, Soma, if you don't mind, we will meet to decide what happened.
To decide what happened?
Yes, to decide what needs to be done.
Adabra has asked that we sanction you, but there's been many things that have been brought up here today that make us question that decision.
We need to meet as a group.
We'll be back in a few minutes.
Oh, boy.
Well, talk amongst yourselves.
The meeting actually goes is over in like 30 seconds.
We judge you guilty.
No, no, no, no.
They turn to you and say, Adabra, they turn to Adabra and say, the case you've made just does not hold.
He says, yes, it is unfortunate that Corbin died, but he was a criminal.
And the part he made the decision, Soma made the decision to save the forest from the dragon.
That was the right decision.
Yes, we like the forest.
And as for your supporters, Adric over here admits that if he were to fall, you admit freely that if we were to listen to you, the orcs, what's going on, is perfectly normal.
And Adric has said that's what he wants to revort.
And then he turns to the Falcon and the Falcon.
The Falcon here depends on money that these interventionists saved him and he needs them to save him.
All you managed to do was offend the bard.
And while he's got some followers, Sister Kaella escaped the Carver did not.
Yes.
And so, as far as we're concerned, the forest is safer.
The forest is safer.
The interventionists, the purpose of the Druids' Enclave is not to save the multiverse.
The purpose of the Druids' Enclave is to save the forest.
Yes.
And to save this region.
And that to just sit there and wait and say that it's all part of some divine cosmic plan, it makes no sense whatsoever.
Right.
They're completely sort of like, she like Adabra's smug look.
Yeah, so you give her a smug look.
Yeah.
She looks at you with sort of an intense rage and then walks out.
Can I mic drop the staff?
Yeah, you can mic drop a staff.
Excellent.
You mic drop the staff.
After the meeting is over, the druids start to pack their things up.
One of them walks up and says, Is there anything you could do to get the bard to come back?
We told he plays very good music.
You're going to have to come see him in Phandalin or when his studio opens.
They're like, We were told he plays very good music.
We were very much looking forward to listening to him play.
Another one says, You know, that thing that after the meeting where everybody's on your side, Adabra was totally uncalled for.
Her behavior was absolutely disgraceful.
Her attack, her personal attacks on Vukradin crossed the line.
So, what do we do about Adabra?
She's left the area.
No, no, I'm asking the other druids: like, what do we do?
You know, she's still a druid at heart, right?
Like, he goes.
He's a Dabra.
They don't know.
The meeting is over.
I just kind of have this image of Druids being something between hippies and Lutherans.
The service is over now.
We're now at the potmark.
All right.
I'm sure it's not the last we've seen of her.
Right.
That's going to be a thing.
Yes.
Well, you let us know if she comes back and, you know, in greater numbers.
And so they're all very pleased.
They do point out that they're very happy that the
wrote down what happens.
All right.
Okay.
So the moderates have sided with you.
Everybody's kind of like this.
Lyra has been given her standing.
She's now part of the, she's now considered a druid in full good standing.
Make Lyra great again.
Yes, yes.
You've successfully made Lyra great again.
So you've acquired a friend and an ally you can call on.
Sort of.
I don't think Vukradin sees her as an ally, but you know.
I'm saying Vukradin's not here.
I'm telling Dave, you know, put a marker on the allies check.
You know, she's very happy.
She wants to buy you all drinks at the Stonehill Tavern.
Like she's like, you know, she's pumped.
She's feeling great.
She's like, you know, this was, she didn't know the site.
She didn't even know that this was possible.
Vukradin is not.
Yeah, Vukradin would not be happy with this outcome, but I understand why everybody else is happy.
Yeah, I'm just not.
This was not a good night.
Hey, it's forest preservation is on the menu.
I'm happy with that.
Right.
So, yes.
All right.
And so the moderates of the Druid Council sides with you, and they agree that this intervention, this naturalist position is anomalous, that it doesn't line up with the callings of the druid, and that they, you know, as far as they are concerned, that this is the last they will listen to this kind of nonsense as far as they're concerned.
Well, not all of it's nonsense, but following it to the extent of Adabra is.
Right.
And what one of them, though, does tell something to you about Meryl.
Like, I mean, they all know about Meryl, so presumably you want to ask them what do they know about Meryl?
Like, because, or do you not want to ask?
I prefer to keep him a mystery for now.
Eric, sounds good.
All right.
Santopoulos walks up to you and says, perhaps Meru made the good choice.
And then he walks off.
Perhaps.
All right.
So you're done with this.
You're done.
You're done with this.
With this whole scene.
You can head back to town and continue with the rest of your quests.
We were on our way somewhere else, I believe, before this got sort of shoehorned in.
You were going to go deal with the Tolosians.
Yeah.
Who were they?
The orcs that the orcs that attacked the Falcon Lodge.
No, I definitely don't want to deal with those people.
Fuck them.
Well, I'm.
I want to go to Neverwinter.
Hold on.
Before you say, I'm just just, I'm totally cool with you wanting to go to Neverwinter.
The only point I would, I just want to make sure that you, as a member of the Privy Council, you know, the orcs are causing harm to the local economy.
I thought all the orcs were going to go back to the Dragon Mountain now that it's free for the taking.
They will if someone like, you know, the problem is the Dragon Mountain was less fertile ground than the forest.
Telling me I got to save the world again.
No, I'm not telling you that.
I'm simply saying that as getting tired of saving the world.
The world doesn't seem to like that I'm saving it.
Dude, what are you talking about?
There was a whole festival congratulating you.
You are that was that was a setup by the mayor to try to gain support for his tenuous political position.
There was genuine love at the con at the meeting.
People were genuinely happy.
Stop feeling the love, man.
Stop feeling it.
Like in the community.
Feeling the angst.
Spider-Man loves you.
I mean, everybody, like the town community loves you.
People want to hear about how you killed the dragon.
That's good.
Right.
I mean, you're a hero.
You're a local celebrity.
And all these druids now that, you know, being dragged through the mud by a druid that I saved for 50 gold pieces.
Yeah, we should have left her at that tower or whatever.
Right.
I'm just saying, man, like Adabra, you know, so Adabra has a stranger who we tried to help and we almost got slaughtered and then he betrayed us.
No, no, you know, he wasn't that.
Well, I mean, Vukradin sees it that way.
Yeah, that's definitely how I see it.
That's not what happened, but that's how, you know, Vukradin, you know, Falcon lost yet another thing.
And, you know, just in that point of week.
I know he's got a lot of trauma.
Yes.
And in that moment of weakness, Adabra managed to convince him that the reason he was failing was because he kept on trying.
Right.
It's true.
If you stop trying, you can't fail.
Yes.
And so he was, he was, he had embraced that, right?
But that's not who he really was.
He was just down.
Well, his, I have marked his quests in red because I am not interested in doing them right now.
The only reason, again, we'll be clear.
The only reason of doing them is that they are endangering the town of Phandalin.
And as a member of its privy council, I'm just saying that would be the only reason.
Did we hire somebody?
Aren't there like other adventurers who want to go deal with the orcs?
I mean, there's always another group of adventurers that could be that you could hire.
I mean, you'd have to pay them money, but they would be not as powerful as you, or if they were as powerful as you, they might have opinions.
I'm just saying, I'm just saying there are checks.
I mean, there's always another adventuring group.
Look, I'm not saying you have to go deal with your orcs.
I'm just saying this is, like I said, don't deal with your orcs.
That's fine.
The world will move forward.
There will be consequences for both good or ill.
You could get the Falcon to come with you.
I mean, he is a high-level ranger.
He likes us.
How would I talk to that guy?
Well, I mean, because Valphine managed to get through to him.
Good for you.
Maybe he can join your church.
Actually, actually, that's actually a very good idea.
In fact, back.
He's looking for direction in his life.
Yes.
No, no, the searing pain.
For a minute, there, actually, do try to.
Make you feel alive.
Just roll a persuasion check.
A religion check, rather, religion.
Religion.
Looking for religion.
He seems like the type.
This is not a strong role, but we will see how this goes.
Oh, wait.
I've got some bonuses here.
Use your bardic inspiration.
Yeah.
Is it 188?
D10.
1810 now, yeah.
That helps a little bit.
What'd you get?
And should I do my bond thing too?
Yes, go for it.
Definitely.
Okay.
So then that would all add up to 18.
Nice.
Much better.
All right.
No, you used your inspiration, right?
I didn't use it successfully, so I still have it.
Oh, so you still have it?
Yeah, I got like a really frummy roll and it did not make it good or enough.
So, so wait, this inspiration is basically you get to keep re-rolling the D10 until until I succeed.
Well, you know, you can reuse it multiple times on one roll.
Yeah.
But it doesn't expire if it didn't if it didn't help you pass the roll, then you keep it.
Okay.
All right.
You rolled an 18, and the Falcon.
So what do you, so, okay, so you achieved an opening.
So what do you tell?
What do you sell him on?
He seems very, very down and dispassionate, you know, to really bring out the zest in life, you know, get a little bit of thrill and sensation.
The pain is a good way to kind of like really get a kick in your life.
This is not the pitch you want to use, but okay.
All right.
So what did you, what did you, what did you, what did you do?
So, sorry, so could you repeat what you said?
My brain just was like trying to process him.
Yeah.
So when I was doing the insight roll earlier, he seemed kind of despondent and kind of like very, very bleed, right?
And so he's a little bit more spice and like thrill and engagement in his life.
He's you know, okay, so it turns out, you know, he's not quite open to being converted.
All right.
Like, this is.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
But, but, you know, what you've done is you've kind of like
you, you kind of like, you know, see, you could, you'd see that he's like refocused his thing.
Like, he's like, he's, he's made a change.
And if you keep working with him, like, you could get him on your, you could get him.
Like, so just to be clear, it's not like he's you're not going to flip, you're not going to flip his entire worldview in one evening.
Okay.
Right.
But, but if you, if you, if you were, for example, to help him with his problem with the orcs, that would go a long way to show, you know, that the power of Lathander.
The power of Lathander, the power of fate.
You know, I'm just presenting like these are things that you get.
You know, the power of politics, right?
And so, you know, but like, yeah.
So, so, so, um,
all right, so that's, um, so that is.
So in this discussion about his pain, do you talk at all about your journey?
He kind of turns to you and says, how did you become a cleric of Lathander?
You're a drow.
Yes, well, you know, I was a menso barad song and you know, after the demons invaded and rampaged the town in response to you know like the predations of uh you know that were instigated by you know like this uh giant uprising right the right so uh you know came up to this to the overbright and wow just the uh the the vividness of the sun beating down on us you know yeah it's a glorious moment it was a glorious moment and i don't know for some reason that clicks with him and he's like you know he goes he he goes he doesn't even know why he ever supported a dabra and he says i've got a lot to work work on and he says we need to go deal with those orcs work on an apology and well and and i was gonna say and he's like i probably owe the braard an apology that would help are you sure about that so but could you like give but he turns to you Valphine and says you're you have a way with words maybe you could convince him that i didn't mean harm
So, but you want to apologize in person?
He wants Valphine to do it.
That is really lame, dude.
No, no, no.
He's asking for how.
He's asking Valphine.
Oh, okay.
Oh, I'd like to hear this.
What's a good way to apologize to be Valphine?
Well, if you have any interesting rare instruments from your lodge, you may donate them to either the church or to the studio.
And I think that would go a long way.
You could build them a performance hall.
These are good ideas.
You got to rebuild your cabin anyway, right?
He goes, well, I mean, I suppose that those are all, those are all, those are all excellent ideas.
Performance hull and a small shrine to Lathander in your lodge.
I don't know.
Does Vukradin play religious music?
Christian rock.
But did I say, like, I'm okay with selling out?
Yeah, no, you've sold out completely, dude.
You'll play whatever people.
Whatever.
Whatever change, man.
Whatever it's about the music.
Yeah, no, it used to be about the art, and then you discovered nobody liked it.
No, there's nothing immoral about selling out.
It's only pathetic.
I think it's that side.
No, I heard you actually thought.
I thought you'd even say that.
I thought it was kind of like you realized that, you know, playing music that nobody wanted to listen to wasn't cool.
No, I think it was that I just want to want everybody to like me.
Yeah, that's what I meant.
You wanted people to like you and play music that nobody liked.
Play what they like.
Sure.
Yeah.
Okay.
Right.
You basically realized that the silver, the eloquence that you acquired, you could apply to yourself.
Yeah, apparently there's no music that'll convince Eldabra.
No, some people are just people have some people are just dicks.
All right.
Okay.
I think so.
1031.
All right.
So anyway, so yes.
So you've managed to navigate this well.
I hope you guys had, I hope you, I hope some of you had fun.
I think Dave starting off with a little, I felt a little slighted, yes.
Well, I mean, you know, I mean, they were, you know, the thing that you have to realize, Dave, is that Vukradin has acquired a reputation of being silver-tongued and convincing everybody with his mouth.
And so he's done it so well that now people, like people who've experienced it firsthand and have been burned by it, get enraged by it, get enraged by it.
So you just have to be aware of that.
Right.
And it's kind of like somebody convinces you of something and you realize they bamboozled you.
Like some reaction, some people overreact.
Right.
So that's what you were experiencing.
It was more them feeling pissed that you had managed to convince them of things and that they had fallen for it and they had seen how you've convinced other people and they were determined that they were going to get their moment.
So that was what was going on.
It wasn't that they it wasn't a it was them feeling like a need to express their power.
The TM just hates you.
That's what it was.
No, that's not that's not true.
I love Vukradin is my favorite character after Valphine and so I mean I love Valphine.
Where's Brewbarry in all of this?
Well if Stefan was here I'd say no I love he loves all his characters equally.
It's just how it is.
I do.
All right.
Anyway guys I hope you guys had fun.
I had fun tonight.
I hope all right.
By the way, just see you guys Sunday.
Quick question.
Where do we want to go next?
Are we going to Neverwinter or are we going to deal with the orcs?
Along the way to Neverwinter.
Yeah, you could make it along the way.
Is it?
As long as you convince Vukradin that we're heading in the direction, he's pretty naive.
He'll probably lose.
We stumble a bunch of orcs.
Just to be able to do that.
We've got to save the world again.
Yeah, just to be clear.
Just to be clear, yes, it's on the way.
It's towards the north.
Now it's towards the east.
And then the work with Vukradin and just, you know.
He's like a child in some ways.
Oh, he's absolutely a child.
Yeah, we're going to Neverwinter.
Yeah, we're there.
Yeah, just a few more days.
We're going to be there.
Okay, so just want to be clear.
So, yes, so it is on the way.
So, orcs and the Neverwinter, is that what we're doing?
Just so I can.
Good night.
I can tire.
Okay.
Guys.
All right.
Question?
Yes, go for it.
So you're saying Sunday?
Yes.
So Saturday.
Is it Saturday?
Well, the LAN party is on Saturday.
Yes.
And then Dave's thing is on Sunday.
Okay.
I don't know about the LAN party.
So for Dave's thing, the are you going?
My thought was I was going, yes.
Okay.
Die RSVP'd.
I have never been up to a game.
I assume people are going to Caltrain.
I'm just going to.
Yeah, I mean, I live right next to Caltrain, so I'm just taking it.
It's like a four-block walk from the station.
Yeah.
Do you can you help me with the logistics?
Maybe I'll see us with you on the train or something.
I mean, it's really easy.
You just get the train.
You get on the train and it's the last station.
Yeah, was it literally the last one?
I forget.
What time, what train are you taking?
Oh, that.
Yeah.
So I'm happy to help you with that, dude.
I'll send you that information.
Yeah.
Have you not been on Caltrain recently?
I haven't been on it since it was electrified, for example.
Oh, yeah.
The new electric trains are nice.
Yeah.
I actually look forward to taking it now.
They've got good Wi-Fi the whole way.
Just zone out.
Yeah.
Well, you know, like if we're all going, we can go hang out on the train, right?
If you want.
Yeah.
I haven't picked the exact train I'm getting on, but you can meet me at Sunnyvale Station.
You can park at my house.
All right.
Okay, folks.
Well, I'd have to go south for Sunnyvale Station.
It's kind of silly.
Mountain View.
So, anyway, hope you guys had fun.
I did.
See you guys Sunday.
Bye.